Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Dance Theatre records, 1963-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Dance Theatre records 1963-1977
Ann Arbor Dance Theatre.
0.5 linear feet
8527 Bp 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan local repertory dance company. Bylaws, board minutes (fragmentary), newsletters, programs, and chronological files; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the organization and were received from Judith L. Kahn (donor no. 6822 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Ann Arbor Dance Theatre was created in 1963 as a repertory dance company. Its founder, Elizabeth Weil, also served as early artistic director. The staff and performers were comprised entirely of volunteers. As a community based company, it was one of the few adult, professionally directed modern dance groups to be organized in this manner.
As a repertory dance company, performances by the Theatre included original, contemporary compositions. These dances were created by a number of individuals who served as the Theatre's choreographers. The company was inactive during several seasons in the 1970's, but was revived for the 1975-1976 calender by Linda Peck and Alice Hinterman. During 1977-1978 it ceased to exist, and Dance Theatre II emerged as its successor.
The records of the Ann Arbor Dance Theatre include both general documents and chronological files from the period 1963-1978. Unfortunately, this is a fragmentary collection. Only scattered runs of newsletters, board minutes, and correspondence remain, with the bulk of papers pertinent to the early years of the organization. Bylaws, financial records, newspaper clippings, announcement of performances and programs are also included. The collection includes a few fragmentary and undated papers as well.
Subjects:
Arts--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies, etc.; Dance--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ailey, Alvin.; Ann Arbor Dance Theatre.; Ballet.; Dance.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Organizational records
  - Bylaws, ca. 1966 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, primarily 1970s (Box 1)
    (including scattered correspondence, lists)
  - Historical Materials (Box 1)
  - Financial Records, ca. 1963-1972 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, ca. 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, mainly 1960s (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1964-ca. 1977 (Box 1)
  - Announcement of Performances (Box 1)
  - Chronological Files, 1963-1977, 6 folders (Box 1)
    (include correspondence, promotional materials, and miscellaneous)
  - Fragmentary and undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs of performances and rehearsals; also photo of Alvin Ailey teaching class (Box 1)